[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d3", "question": "What event in a decathlon takes the athletes to the greatest height?", "answer": "Pole vault", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017401844491cbd7c5a17ba", "question": "Who was the only one of Henry VIII\u2019s wives to receive a Queen\u2019s funeral?", "answer": "Jane Seymour", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339944", "question": "What actress was Tom Cruise\u2019s first wife?", "answer": "Mimi Rogers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed2", "question": "What happened to Barry Allen after lightning struck the chemicals in his lab?", "answer": "He turned into the Flash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdcdcec223966ae8f88f9", "question": "What actor played the role of Margaret White in the 2013 film \"Carrie\"?", "answer": "Julianne Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a3d212f2a7826b9b8729", "question": "What is the atomic number for Palladium?", "answer": "46", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ec7ffe83fe1f2a824c03", "question": "Who in the New Testament got shipwrecked on one of his missionaries?", "answer": "Paul", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c467", "question": "What is the proper term for a young eel?", "answer": "An elver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600399ab57a0e35c43f8389e", "question": "What artist first achieved notoriety through graffiti epigrams?", "answer": "Jean-Michel Basquiat\u00a0first achieved notoriety as part of SAMO, an informal graffiti duo who wrote enigmatic epigrams.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c661", "question": "What is the chemical process for converting sugar into alcohol?", "answer": "Fermentation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4ba949076251badbeac6", "question": "The first North American\u00a0English seasonal camp was founded where?", "answer": "St. John's, Newfoundland -- In 1583, Sir\u00a0Humphrey Gilbert, by the\u00a0royal prerogative\u00a0of\u00a0Queen Elizabeth I, founded\u00a0St. John's.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a0decf93664eb10486bb", "question": "The \"Ugu Youth\" radio station is broadcast in which African country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df0", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"catamaran\"?", "answer": "Tamil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4d9b2008b8581f80b092c2", "question": "Gord Downie, who passed away on October 17, 2017, was the lead singer of which Canadian rock band?", "answer": "The Tragically Hip", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ea77b24f84e0b9f9ffd4", "question": "Vermiphobia, helminthophobia, or scoleciphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Worms, especially parasitic ones", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ccc", "question": "The song \"Suite: Judy Blue Eyes\" was inspired by Stephen Stills' breakup with whom?", "answer": "Judy Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e80537de59ea584496fea9", "question": "Which dog is named for the German word for snout?", "answer": "Schnauzer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae927e574a5ce6b56b822e", "question": "What type of lettuce should be used in a classic Caesar Salad?", "answer": "Romaine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa40", "question": "What country's explorers discovered the site of Pensacola, Florida?", "answer": "Spain's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ed9606d333868d34d76e", "question": "In what type of language does the meaning change based on your pitch?", "answer": "Tonal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd143ec223966ae8f88be", "question": "What actor wore prosthetic ears while filming \"Jupiter Ascending\"?", "answer": "Channing Tatum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa33", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Minnesota?", "answer": "Saint Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfdd", "question": "What was the first product to have a barcode?", "answer": "Wrigley's gum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c028d22ea32143fcb1d3b56", "question": "Who wrote the play \"Heartbreak House: A Fantasia in the Russian Manner on English Themes\"?", "answer": "George Bernard Shaw", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66b51a5bfecdd737e0884", "question": "The Fig Newton was named after a suburb of what city?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86c", "question": "In a game of Hearts, what term describes winning every heart and the queen of spades?", "answer": "Shooting the Moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d17", "question": "What year was Beethoven born in?", "answer": "1770", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede1066ce05a3942286dc0", "question": "What city did Frank Sinatra help immortalize as \"That Toddlin' Town\"?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "593c4b58b8198b9a2b077962", "question": "The film \"Casablanca\" takes place during which global conflict?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fc", "question": "What is missing from a navel orange?", "answer": "Seeds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb4437e83c707845b2118", "question": "Water deer have what unique feature?", "answer": "Tusks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb97d7e83c707845b2139", "question": "What do mercury and bromine have in common?", "answer": "They are liquid at room temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f1", "question": "What wondrous creation was designed by Sostratus of Cnidus?", "answer": "Lighthouse of Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989ae11cb8751d53e7d7613", "question": "What is the name of the pub in the 1945 film \"Pink String and Sealing Wax\"?", "answer": "The Dolphin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f753da9e54d890926f707", "question": "How long is New Zealand\u2019s Ninety Mile Beach?", "answer": "55 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52e", "question": "What is the main difference between a Bloody Mary and a Bloody Caeser?", "answer": "Mary is made with Tomato juice and Caesar is made with Clamato juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c4", "question": "What commonly used drug is also used as a natural pesticide?", "answer": "Caffeine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b9", "question": "What is measured in Watts?", "answer": "Power", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2c", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Fat City\"?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbad", "question": "What two words did Jim Henson combine to come up with the word \"muppet\"?", "answer": "marionette and puppet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abdb", "question": "What is Canberra's Telstra Tower also known as?", "answer": "Black Mountain Tower", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c987", "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure?", "answer": "Giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3ad4ff048f679a45ab2f", "question": "What is the shape of DNA known as?", "answer": "Double Helix", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339655", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who invented the drink \"The Flaming Moe\"?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd03", "question": "It is sometimes considered a fashion faux pas to wear white after what holiday?", "answer": "Labor Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab2", "question": "Who wrote the Christmas murder-mystery, Star Bright! A Christmas Story?", "answer": "Andrew M. Greeley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f7b", "question": "Which novelist sometimes writes under the pseudonym Richard Bachman?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000f0ee9a72b906b34e3cfe", "question": "Which part of a cow does chuck meat come from?", "answer": "Shoulder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9c", "question": "Yaren is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Nauru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a63ea2ebb971c1417fb9e", "question": "Which famous classical composer's music was featured in the film \"Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "Beethoven's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3a8fc73aa70ea0b70adf", "question": "What is the oldest city in the world?", "answer": "Damascus (The capital of Syria has evidence of continuous habitation dating back at least 11,000 years)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d117d64fea7fe947a2227e", "question": "Which German firm produced the World War II plane known as the Condor?", "answer": "Focke-Wulf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c531", "question": "What is the first element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a6", "question": "What name did Nathaniel Dwayne Hale adopt, to hype his pedigree as Snoop Dogg's cousin?", "answer": "Nate Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa1620565ad31a57c810", "question": "Who was the President Kennedy's Secretary of Defense?", "answer": "Robert McNamara", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6017375e44491cbd7c5a1789", "question": "Who designed and built the interior structure of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "The innovative designer and builder Gustave Eiffel and his structural engineer, Maurice Koechlin designed and built the statue.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c9b49076251badbead8", "question": "Who was the first American to orbit the Earth?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He orbited the Earth three times in five hours in a Mercury space capsule he named \"Friendship 7\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ef23fe83fe1f2a824c0d", "question": "General Tso chicken is named after which Chinese historical figure?", "answer": "Zuo Zongtang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e5", "question": "What sport has its name abbreviated to BMX?", "answer": "Bicycle Moto-cross", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7d", "question": "Who was president when the agency that would become the FBI was created?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c676877e98cb977789b9", "question": "What US state is home to the Lost Sea?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d5", "question": "What European city is known as the \"Eternal City\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2b", "question": "Who starred in the title role of the 2007 film \"Mr. Brooks\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a81", "question": "In what country was Arnold Schwarzenegger born?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a801", "question": "Which US state's flag is the only one with a Union Jack on it?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a0", "question": "According to the Gospels, what did the Wise Men bring?", "answer": "Gold, Frankincense, and Myrrh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a6", "question": "What was Betty Rubble's maiden name?", "answer": "McBricker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600780f8bd51d85e222ab646", "question": "What is the main visual element in Impressionist painting?", "answer": "They were interested in trying to capture the changing effects of light by using a more exact analysis of tone and color.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4c5049076251badbead1", "question": "The term \"first family\" came into popularity under which U.S. President?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy -- Comedian/Kennedy impressionist Vaughn Meader titled his Grammy-winning 1962 album \"First Family\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff212b431a458464a93c44b", "question": "Originally, Jack-O'-lanterns were made from which type of vegetable?", "answer": "Turnip", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339efa", "question": "Who won a 1991 best male vocalist Grammy despite having died in 1988?", "answer": "Roy Orbison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc11c0469bb8041d07a079", "question": "What is the name of a popular Italian orange and vanilla flavored liqueur?", "answer": "Tuaca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a540", "question": "Lopez Island, Orcas Island and Waldron Island all belong to what archipelago?", "answer": "San Juan Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba61", "question": "What is the international radio code word for the letter \u2018Y\u2019?", "answer": "Yankee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0a", "question": "Hockey player Wayne Gretzky was born in what Canadian city?", "answer": "Brantford, Ontario", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cefc001948005ec986edcd9", "question": "On the day George Washington was first inaugurated as President of the United States, how many United States were there?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff516c5ff04d658268c92f4", "question": "Who was the first President to use the Oval Office?", "answer": "William Howard Taft", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f8d0fe83fe1f2a824c2f", "question": "Who are the first people known to have consumed chocolate?", "answer": "Olmecs. There is evidence that the ancient Olmecs of what is now Mexico consumed chocolate beverages as far back as 1900 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e482fe83fe1f2a824bb5", "question": "In the last six months of the war, what was the U.S. strategy for winning the conflict with Japan?", "answer": "Break the Japanese will with massive bombing raids on Japanese cities", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b9", "question": "What comedic duo starred in the movie \"Stir Crazy\"?", "answer": "Gene Wilder and Richard Pryor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946a", "question": "In what decade does the movie \"Girl, Interrupted\" take place?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b571c6767df192a942e3374", "question": "What three countries border the Togolese Republic?", "answer": "Ghana, Benin and Burkina Faso", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bac", "question": "What band's first Top 10 hit in the US was 1984's \"Legs\"?", "answer": "ZZ Top", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e5bffe83fe1f2a824bc4", "question": "In the Bible, Jesus referred to the disciples James and John as Sons of whom?", "answer": "Thunder", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339179", "question": "Who were the five members of sixties Rat Pack?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra, Sammy Davis Jr., Dean Martin, Peter Lawford, Joey Bishop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b7", "question": "What are brails and buntlines on a ship?", "answer": "Ropes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7bfec2b316f4693fb6796", "question": "Where is the goat-racing capital of the world?", "answer": "Tobago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a62e32ebb971c1417fb94", "question": "The \"Turbot War\" was a fishing dispute between Canada and what other country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b981", "question": "What used to be called the apple of love or love apple ?", "answer": "The tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6990a20565ad31a57c73f", "question": "What legendary athlete lit the Olympic torch at the 1996 Atlanta Olympics?", "answer": "Mohammed Ali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65c261f3c0ead6880d60e", "question": "Which US fast food burger chain celebrated its 86th birthday in 2007?", "answer": "Whte Castle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e3", "question": "Which US president lived in Walker's Point?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd64", "question": "In what US state are submarine sandwiches traditionally called \"po' boys\"?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3f11c8b5801b8f54a7fbd", "question": "Which famed European palace inspired Washington, D.C.'s design?", "answer": "Versailles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b3", "question": "Who is the main character in Joseph Heller's novel \"Catch-22\"?", "answer": "Yossarian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398cb", "question": "What 1968 movie starred Jack Lemmon and Walter Matthau sharing an apartment?", "answer": "The Odd Couple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c7c49076251badbead5", "question": "Which newspaper incorrectly reported Thomas E. Dewey defeated Harry S. Truman in the 1948 U.S. Presidential Election?", "answer": "Chicago Daily Tribune -- Now known as Chicago Tribune, it had once referred to Truman as a \"nincompoop\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacb", "question": "What is the International Criminal Police Organization better known as?", "answer": "Interpol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae85ff94007905755f79e8d", "question": "What is the nickname of The Ganges-Brahmaputra Delta, the largest delta in the world?", "answer": "The Green Delta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339659", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Snake's car?", "answer": "Li'l Bandit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0ecff048f679a45aaab", "question": "Verminophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Germs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5b7f6ce05a3942286e16", "question": "Where are the doldrums?", "answer": "Near the equator", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0a", "question": "If you have singultus, what do you suffer from?", "answer": "Hiccups", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5989ac05cb8751d53e7d7608", "question": "\"Speak, Memory\" is an autobiographical memoir by which Russian author?", "answer": "Vladimir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b049e662d71a53650fc5", "question": "The roof of Spain\u2019s Dal\u00ed Theatre-Museum is lined with what?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede1366ce05a3942286dc3", "question": "In the 2006 movie \"Flicka,\" what type of animal is Flicka?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a47112f2a7826b9b8730", "question": "A medicine that hastens the emptying of the bowels is called a what?", "answer": "Laxative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5971dd8e89261e916c8e099e", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1990\u2019s TV show \"Grace Under Fire\"?", "answer": "Brett Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aecc", "question": "Where was South Africa's Freedom Charter signed?", "answer": "Kliptown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c2694f032c0db195b481", "question": "How old was Catherine of Aragon when she was betrothed to Prince Arthur?", "answer": "Catherine was three years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067b35ff9c0647b50a8061", "question": "With what global issue does the 2016 Paris Agreement deal with?", "answer": "Climate change", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c54", "question": "Whitney Houston's self-titled debut album was released in what year?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf1", "question": "What is the world\u2019s largest diamond company?", "answer": "De Beers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c35aa815febcc896f925f", "question": "In which country would you most likely find the traditional Mariachi bands?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339131", "question": "What year was the first half of \"The Faerie Queene\" epic poem published?", "answer": "1590", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008b61cf842fa4c4ba9698", "question": "How was American comedian and actor, William Claude Dukenfield, better known as?", "answer": "WC Fields\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a5", "question": "In the game of poker, who was the hand referred to as \"dead man's hand\" named after?", "answer": "Wild Bill Hickok", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c314", "question": "What irrational mathematical constant is known as the golden ratio?", "answer": "1.6180339887", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b135", "question": "The Gadsden Purchase involved the lower portions of what are now which two US states?", "answer": "Arizona and New Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6d", "question": "What is known as Ireland's \"kissing rock\"?", "answer": "The Blarney Stone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03c", "question": "What was the name of the sect that was raided by the FBI in Waco, Texas in 1993?", "answer": "Branch Davidians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02f", "question": "What country presented the US with a gift of cherry trees in 1912?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffcc31cf6db9ac4808d03", "question": "What is the longest bridge in the San Francisco Bay Area?", "answer": "San Mateo-Hayward Bridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa5ad73838c5c8a417f29", "question": "What do speleologists study?", "answer": "Wild cave systems", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a395", "question": "What continent is Jamaica considered part of?", "answer": "North America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c232", "question": "What computer language was named after Ada Lovelace?", "answer": "Ada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff25a9031a458464a93c473", "question": "What Dr. Seuss character was featured on the writer's license plate?", "answer": "The Grinch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0bb", "question": "Mace is the outer covering of which common spice?", "answer": "Nutmeg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad09", "question": "What was Albert Einstein's first job after graduating from Zurich Polytechnic?", "answer": "Patent clerk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdd60e10499cffc60b84239", "question": "Who wrote the 95 Thesis against the Catholic Church?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf48", "question": "Transom, poop and keel are all parts of a what?", "answer": "Boat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8c", "question": "When did Arizona and New Mexico become states?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e5", "question": "What was the Allie's code name for the \"D-Day\" invasion of Normandy?", "answer": "Operation Overlord", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c9", "question": "Who was the US's first postmaster general?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc8559fabc30a8194e188ae", "question": "Who starred in both of the films \"Jaws\" and \"The Deep\"?", "answer": "Robert Shaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e4", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a short tube?", "answer": "Ditalini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b35b01dd7bf43be5e7ad", "question": "A group of elephants is called what?", "answer": "A parade or memory", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e7", "question": "What year was Neptune discovered?", "answer": "1846", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4db", "question": "In what country would you look for the Loch Ness Monster?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f07", "question": "What author created the character of Father Brown?", "answer": "G. K. Chesterton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d4", "question": "What 1994 cult film featured a day in the lives of characters Dante and Randal?", "answer": "Clerks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae950e574a5ce6b56b8250", "question": "What is the capital of Malawi?", "answer": "Lilongwe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b8e2e662d71a53651029", "question": "The line \"All of this happened, more or less.\" starts what novel?", "answer": "\"Slaughterhouse-Five\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93d856bd93ce3a4e5f6b7", "question": "In which type of chemical bonding are electrons shared between adjacent atoms?", "answer": "Covalent", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb666b5dad637d903c8836", "question": "Which English city was Alfred the Great's capital city?", "answer": "Winchester", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af52", "question": "Against which country did Hitler launch \u201cOperation Barbarossa\u201d?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e3", "question": "Whose band was \"The Quarrymen\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be4a", "question": "Keurig Green Mountain is responsible for inventing what product?", "answer": "K-cup pods", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d057b1a1c922dd1ac64a2", "question": "What is Ronald Biggs famous for?", "answer": "Being one of the \"Great Train Robbers\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c503", "question": "What actually is a shooting star?", "answer": "A meteor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b336", "question": "In which country was the Rosetta Stone found?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de9", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"wok\"?", "answer": "Cantonese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b18f", "question": "The Parthenon in Greece was dedicated to which Greek Goddess?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c517", "question": "What is a cross between a blackberry and a raspberry?", "answer": "Boysenberry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015dfd6fe83fe1f2a824b81", "question": "Who wrote the first algorithm intended to be carried out by a machine?", "answer": "Ada Lovelace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe939a66bd93ce3a4e5f68f", "question": "What term describes the center of gravity of the Earth and moon?", "answer": "Barycenter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ec7227f57c9fcac0ce71976", "question": "What is the longest running sporting event in the United States?", "answer": "The Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339943", "question": "What is the first rule in the movie \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "You don't talk about Fight Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd3", "question": "What instrument did jazz bandleader Count Basie play?", "answer": "Piano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe90a5a01dd7bf43be5e89b", "question": "Who invented the alternating current motor?", "answer": "Nikola Tesla", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f7d3fe83fe1f2a824c27", "question": "A young women in the 1920's that behaved and dressed boldly was referred to as what?", "answer": "A flapper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c4", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering Penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb6b865ff7d326b622a99", "question": "What US city is named after Saint Francis of Assisi?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d9a22596a59cbdfbd3c8", "question": "In many Old West cities, the colorful phrase \"Boot Hill\" referred to what?", "answer": "Cemetery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ed", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for iron?", "answer": "Fe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c94", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Quahog, Rhode Island?", "answer": "The Family Guy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c50", "question": "Who directed the 1968 \"Planet of the Apes\" movie?", "answer": "Franklin J. Schaffner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fc", "question": "In which 1966 science fiction film did Stephen Boyd star alongside Raquel Welch?", "answer": "Fantastic Voyage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab97", "question": "Which sea separates Greece from Asia Minor?", "answer": "Aegean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ab", "question": "Which company is the largest manufacturer of tires?", "answer": "Lego", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940f", "question": "What was the maiden name of \"Leave It to Beaver\" TV mom June Cleaver?", "answer": "Bronson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd660a8a5bfecdd737e0836", "question": "What did \"RMS\" in RMS Titanic stand for?", "answer": "Royal Mail Ship", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc0246de0eb824d4052d7", "question": "What city is known as the \"polar bear capital of the world\"?", "answer": "Churchill, Manitoba -- It's fairly common to see one strolling through the Canadian town or outside one's bedroom window at night.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c60", "question": "What liqueur was Vincent Van Gogh said to be heavily drinking heavily the night he cut off his ear?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad0a", "question": "Who designed the Vietnam Veterans memorial in Washington DC?", "answer": "Maya Lin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a784", "question": "How many US state capital city\u2019s names begin with the letter \"S\"?", "answer": "6", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e93a7b2d6f11f394a3b2d57", "question": "In the manga series \"Bleach\", what is the name of Ichigo's zanpakuto?", "answer": "Zangetsu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65585ae7e414034b5aeb3", "question": "Which country started the tradition of building gingerbread houses?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd820ecd0de9af39e9d46a0", "question": "What state is home to US' oldest newspaper still being printed?", "answer": "Connecticut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fef", "question": "What is divided into 114 suras?", "answer": "The Quran", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b6", "question": "What does a \"caliber\" measure?", "answer": "The approximate internal diameter of a gun barrel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd9dae347d002c297e4d0", "question": "What became the tallest building in London after its official opening in October 1965?", "answer": "Post Office Tower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339723", "question": "Bruce Springsteen was given what nickname?", "answer": "The Boss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e957b24f84e0b9f9ffcc", "question": "Seretse Khama was the first President of which African country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b63", "question": "What shape is the scar on Harry Potter's forehead?", "answer": "Lightning Bolt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f5652d33a95c66dc4fe755", "question": "Which cluster of stars is also known as the Seven Sisters?", "answer": "The Pleiades", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded065ea2747c8aff16d27", "question": "In which city would you find the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4d", "question": "In 1819, the US purchased Florida from what country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f68a01dd7bf43be5e832", "question": "What are the holes in Swiss cheese called?", "answer": "Eyes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a928", "question": "Where is the Bowling Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Arlington, Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b341", "question": "John Augustus Larson invented what in 1921?", "answer": "Lie detector (Polygraph)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ee", "question": "In the 1988 movie \"Die Hard\", what does John McClane leave in the limo?", "answer": "A teddy bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f521ff048f679a45aad2", "question": "Nosocomephobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Hospitals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a8d", "question": "In the series \"Eragon\", what is the name of Eragon's dragon?", "answer": "Saphira", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab8", "question": "What nationality was the chemist Alfred Nobel?", "answer": "Swedish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b810", "question": "What is traditionally hidden in a Mardi Gras king cake?", "answer": "A small plastic baby doll", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339945", "question": "What is the last name of the three brothers part of the original Beach Boys?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a508", "question": "The city of Machu Picchu is located in which country?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e7", "question": "What does a pedometer count?", "answer": "Steps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b678", "question": "A \"top-sider\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d3", "question": "In which country was the singer Mika born?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e80", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The Short-Timers\" set?", "answer": "Vietnam War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd852ec223966ae8f88db", "question": "What 1980 film has a character named Lacey Underall?", "answer": "\"Caddyshack\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a1826c0f9723ab15cb3a", "question": "Who was the first honorary citizen of the U.S.?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d08181a1c922dd1ac64bf", "question": "Ulaanbaatar is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6013709c1381754895396383", "question": "Actor Earl Hindman always hid behind a fence in which '90s TV show?", "answer": "\"Home Improvement\", which aired from 1991 to 1999.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c939", "question": "In what organ of the body is insulin produced?", "answer": "Pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339256", "question": "What is the name of the mob boss who hires the gang in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Joe Cabot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078be90eee65b76b9f266e", "question": "In which country did the first World War I battle take place?", "answer": "Belgium (The first official battle of WWI occurred at the city named Liege. The city was taken by Germany by August 15, 1914.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad9", "question": "What was the common archaic name for a giraffe?", "answer": "Camelopard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6aa", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for the element Magnesium on the periodic table?", "answer": "Mg", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e72", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Butterflies Are Free\"?", "answer": "Edward Albert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd4c877e98cb97778a34", "question": "What was the first country to declare internet a legal right?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a960", "question": "What largest lake of Central America is home to unusual freshwater sharks?", "answer": "Lake Nicaragua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76a09eec85e375820b2b8", "question": "True champagne can only come from grapes grown in the Champagne region of what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f9", "question": "Who played Jack Nicholson's wife in the 1980 film \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "Shelley Duvall\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c4", "question": "Though botanically a fruit, what food was officially ruled a vegetable by the US Supreme Court in 1893?", "answer": "The tomato", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008dde8f4f3bc4a292f8625", "question": "Which country holds the record for the longest period without a government during peacetime?", "answer": "Belgium holds the record for longest period without a government in peacetime, at 541 days. It occurred during 2010 to 2011.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf2", "question": "What was the official name for the World War II evacuation of Dunkirk?", "answer": "Operation Dynamo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad52", "question": "What was the real first name of the First Lady known as Mamie Eisenhower?", "answer": "Mary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe656adae7e414034b5aecf", "question": "Which King of England was faced with the Peasants' Revolt in 1381?", "answer": "Richard II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "595247c2736d4be723796b73", "question": "What is the name of Lady Antebellum\u2019s first #1 hit?", "answer": "\"I Run To You\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a199", "question": "Who plays Snow White in the film \"Snow White and The Huntsman\"?", "answer": "Kristen Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa7", "question": "What actress starred simultaneously on \"Dynasty\" and \"T.J. Hooker\" during the  early 1980s?", "answer": "Heather Locklear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a336", "question": "Who played Laurie Strode in the 1978 horror film \"Halloween\"?", "answer": "Jamie Lee Curtis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59a", "question": "What is the collective name for chicken, ducks and turkeys in the wild?", "answer": "Fowl", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a7f51a6f5f79087132fb3d", "question": "What do British people call zucchini?", "answer": "Courgette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062ac3c9d816e292245c1b", "question": "What American artist is known for the Nurse Paintings?", "answer": "The Nurse Paintings are a series by Richard Prince inspired by the covers and titles of pulp romance novels.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59774295284458f1d7854421", "question": "What contestant-based reality television series aired in the United States originated in Holland?", "answer": "The Voice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e4", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Georgia?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c9", "question": "What TV show featured a character by the name of Christmas Snow?", "answer": "Three's Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c18e", "question": "What liqueur is prepared from cumin, caraway seeds and fennel?", "answer": "Kummel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c7130775fa611bce67d5", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"Sic semper tyrannis\" mean?", "answer": "\"Thus always to tyrants\" -- It is short for \"Sic semper tyrannis ad mortem\", which means \"Thus always I bring death to tyrants\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929e", "question": "In \"Ferris Bueller's Day Off\", who is the \"Sausage King of Chicago\"?", "answer": "Abe Froman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa57fbc73aa70ea0b70b37", "question": "Which U.S. state features the Italian phrase \"Fatti maschii, parole femine\" as its state motto?", "answer": "Maryland  (The motto translates as \u201cManly deeds, womanly words.\u201d\u00a0 The state uses\u00a0\"Strong deeds, gentle words\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab05", "question": "What did Temujin change his name to?", "answer": "Genghis Khan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dab", "question": "What hitmaker produced the 2003 PlayStation music mixer game \"Beaterator\"?", "answer": "Timbaland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3f1e44f0f6af5b066650", "question": "Morello is a variety of which fruit?", "answer": "Cherry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00d", "question": "The Titanic sank while on its way to what city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339493", "question": "What does Phil do for a living in the movie \"Groundhog Day\"?", "answer": "He is a weatherman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338912", "question": "What flowers did van Gogh paint most regularly?", "answer": "Sunflowers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff7c1662b316f4693fb679d", "question": "Which famous sandwich was formerly known as the Blue Ribbon Burger?", "answer": "Big Mac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c56", "question": "When was the book \u201cNational Velvet\u201d first published?", "answer": "1935", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf8", "question": "N'Djamena is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c374c815febcc896f926f", "question": "Who wrote the detective novel \"The Maltese Falcon\"?", "answer": "Dashiell Hammett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389bd", "question": "What name is given to the metal bars running across the neck of a guitar?", "answer": "Frets", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecca05ec223966ae8f8897", "question": "What is the name of the alien race who were the adoptive parents of Samus in the \"Metroid\" franchise?", "answer": "The Chozo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe657b5ae7e414034b5aee1", "question": "In the \"Book of Malachi\", God says that he has left the kingdom of Esau to which animals?", "answer": "Jackals", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd668fda5bfecdd737e0875", "question": "How many eyes does a honey bee have?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339657", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", the words across the front of the Springfield museum say \"Truth, Knowledge and...\" what?", "answer": "Gift shop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121aac63c99d48cd169b05", "question": "What was the first patented service uniform in the United States?", "answer": "Playboy bunny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59636d8d967692ea851899ad", "question": "The surface of what is typically 70% water and 10% ice?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb60665ff7d326b622a93", "question": "Under what title was Agatha Christie's \"Murder on the Orient Express\" first published in the US?", "answer": "Murder on the Calais Coach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f457caf848b908361b873", "question": "Who became president of Brazil in 2019?", "answer": "Jair Bolsonaro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af25961b63e5727cf5a484d", "question": "Celine Dion's \"My Heart Will Go On\" song was featured as the main theme song to which 1990's movie?", "answer": "Titanic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c1", "question": "Which actress was awarded \"Sexiest Woman of the Century\" honors by People magazine in 1999?", "answer": "Marilyn Monroe", "category": "entertainment"}]